(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T13:43:42.116585",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
もう振り返らず歩いて行けるさ
I can walk on without looking back
いつかまた逢うその日まで
until the day we meet again.
君の夢がきっと叶うように
So that your dream will surely come true,
あの星に願っているよ
I'm wishing upon that star.
もうすぐ逢えなくなる
Soon we won't be able to meet,
君の突然の言葉
your sudden words.
何も考えられず
Unable to think of anything at all,
ただうつむいた
I just hung my head.
夜も眠れずに涙をこらえて
Unable to sleep at night, holding back my tears,
ずっと答えを探してた
I kept searching for the answer.
だけど本当に君が好きだから
But because I truly love you,
信じ続けたい
I want to keep believing.
もう振り返らず歩いて行けるさ
I can walk on without looking back
いつかまた逢うその日まで
until the day we meet again.
君の夢がきっと叶うように
So that your dream will surely come true,
あの星に願っているよ
I'm wishing upon that star.
どんなに遠く二人離れても
No matter how far apart we are,
ずっと君を想っている
I'll always be thinking of you.
この寂しさを乗り越えられたら
If I can overcome this loneliness,
きっと笑顔でまた逢える
I'm sure we'll meet again with a smile.
やがて時は流れて 何事もない毎日
Before long, time flowed on, with uneventful days,
ただ穏やかな日々が流れていった
just peaceful days passing by.
遠く離れても二人の写真は
Even far apart, our photographs
いつも笑顔でいてくれる
always keep us smiling.
見知らぬ場所で君が輝くから
Since you shine in an unfamiliar place,
弱さは見せない
I won't show any weakness.
悲しさよりも未来の幸せ
More than sadness, believing in future happiness,
信じて強く生きていたい
I want to live strongly.
遠回りしてでも掴む夢に
Even taking a detour, the dream I grasp
きっと意味があるのだから
surely has meaning.
海を渡り行く鳥たちのように
Like birds crossing across the sea,
君に会いに行けるのなら
if I could go to see you,
ただ今まで通り頑張ってと
Just telling you to keep doing your best,
ただ一言伝えたい
I just want to say one word.
辛い時にはあの歌を思い出す
At painful times, I remember that song,
君の声が胸の奥で響き渡る
your voice echoes deep within my heart.
もう振り返らず歩いて行けるさ
I can keep walking without looking back,
いつかまた逢うその日まで
until the day we meet again.
君の夢がきっと思うように
Hoping your dreams will surely come true,
あの星に願っているよ
I'm wishing upon that star.
どんなに遠く二人離れても
No matter how far apart we are,
ずっと君を想っている
I'll always be thinking of you.
この寂しさを乗り越えられたら
If we can overcome this loneliness,
きっと笑顔でまた逢える
I'm sure we'll meet again with a smile.
忘れないで
Don't forget,
don't forget,
忘れないで
don't forget.
願い続けているよ
I'm wishing for it.
え、ちょっとマイク取られちゃった感じだけど、
Um, it feels like my mic got taken away a bit,
もういっか。
but oh well.
みんな！ペコらの生誕ライブに来てくれて、ありペコー！
Everyone! Thanks for coming to Pekora's birthday live, thanks-peko!
本日のハッシュタグは「うさぎぺこら生誕祭2025」たくさんつぶやいてね！
Today's hashtag is #UsadaPekoraBirthday2025, so please tweet lots!
というわけで、もう1曲目の曲からなんとなく「あれ？今回のライブのテーマ、あれなのかな？」って思った人もいると思いますが、
That said, from the very first song, some of you might have wondered, 'Wait, is that the theme of this live?'
まずはステージを、見てくださーい！
but first, please take a look at the stage!
どらぁ、すごいな！なんだこれは！これはなんだぁ！
Whoa, amazing! What is this?! What on earth is this?!
ということでね、まあこの後ちょっとゲストパートもあるペコなんですけども、
So, well, after this there's going to be a guest part too, peko,
まあみんなが知ってる曲だったりとか、もしかしたら知らない曲もあるかとは思いますが、
and well, there'll be songs everyone knows, and maybe some songs you don't know, but
めちゃめちゃね楽しい曲もありますので、お楽しみに！
there are also super fun songs, so please look forward to it!
というわけで、じゃあ早速行ってきまーすしょう！ではでは！
With that, let's head right in! Now then, bye-bye!
スーパーぺこらBONUS
Super Pekora Bonus
自分の過去に囚われ迷って
Trapped and lost in my own past,
そうじゃないよと言い聞かせて
telling myself that's not true,
全てを自由に操れるかなんて
wondering if I can freely control everything—
分からないよと霞んで正解はどこ？
blurry and unclear, where is the correct answer?
僕の手のひらに残る大事なもの
What remains in the palm of my hand is something precious,
忘れない記憶何度でも君を守り抜くと叫んで
an unforgettable memory, shouting that I will protect you no matter how many times.
巻き戻しの中掴んだ相棒と
Together with the partner I grasped amidst the rewind,
離しはしないから
I will never let go.
散らばりだした想い今一度絆の願いへ
Scattered feelings, once more toward the wish of our bonds.
胸に抱いた思い出とずっと あの日からの続く決意で 飛べるよ
with the memories held in our chest and the determination continuing from that day, we can fly!
まだ遠いけど君がいれば
Though it's still far, if you're here,
少しは強くなれる気がして明日の色を重ねるんだ
I feel like I can grow a bit stronger, layering tomorrow's colors.
呼んだ希望辿って止めた世界を超えた
Tracing the hope I called upon, I crossed the paused world.
諦めない想いいつしか心繋げた
Feelings of not giving up eventually connected our hearts.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Even if crying, let's smile and go meet tomorrow.
決めた誓い辛くて倒れても
Even if we fall, weighed down by the oath we made,
君のココロを守るため
to protect your heart.
記憶のない時の中にきっと求めていた温かさはあって
There was surely warmth that I sought within times without memories.
包まれた瞬間すべての想いは君へ巡る
The moment I was wrapped in it, all my feelings revolve toward you.
空に向かって走り手にしたいくつもの尊い光胸にしまって
Stretching toward the sky, keeping in my chest the many precious lights I obtained by running,
私の中の輝きに変え迷いを全部払って飛ぼう
turning them into radiance within me, banishing all hesitation as I soar.
正解の見えない入り組んだ迷路を抜け君が流した涙で心目覚めた
Escaping the intricate maze with no clear answer, my heart awakened by the tears you shed.
そして知った世界はこんなにもまだ綺麗で新しい可能性を生むだろう
And the world I came to know is still so beautiful, surely giving birth to new possibilities.
時のカケラの願いから
From the wish of time's fragments...
すくい信じて割れた想い
Feelings scooped up, believed in, and shattered,
私が始まりに立て
I stood at the beginning,
君の笑顔取り戻すよ真実の奇跡になって
recovering your smile, becoming a true miracle.
呼んだ希望辿って止めた世界を超えた
Tracing the hope I called upon, I crossed the paused world.
諦めない想いいつしか心繋げた
Feelings of not giving up eventually connected our hearts.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Even if crying, let's smile and go meet tomorrow.
決めた誓い辛くて倒れても
Even if we fall, weighed down by the oath we made,
君のココロを守るため
to protect your heart.
君の君の側にいよう
Let's be by your side, by your side.
GET UP GET DOWN 闘いの時
GET UP GET DOWN, time for battle.
脆弱な心のままに全てかけて
With a frail heart, betting everything,
守るべきものがあるはず
there must be something worth protecting.
一人で生きてくそんな言葉
Living all alone... words like that.
癒えぬままの
Unhealed...
孤高を逆撫でる
stroking raw isolation.
哀しみは怒りへと 行き場求め
Sorrow seeks a destination in anger,
かつて、祈りであった唄は
the song that once was a prayer
調和失い 心侵すの
losing its harmony and invading the heart.
半端な 強さじゃもはや
Half-baked strength is no longer enough,
愚かなプライドさえ護れない
unable to protect even foolish pride.
薄幸な 月が嘲笑う
The fickle moon mocks us.
不穏に揺らぐ正義
Justice trembles uneasily,
空虚に喘ぎながら
gasping in the emptiness,
それでも希望を狂い求める
yet still madly seeking hope.
守るべきものがあるはず
There must be something worth protecting.
勝利者の足元で誰かが泣いてる
Someone is weeping at the victor's feet.
立ち負けを避けれないこの日々の中
Within these days where defeat cannot be avoided,
悔しさを吐き口でこぼして行くような
spilling out frustration through venting,
臆病な奴にはもうなりたくない
I no longer want to be a coward.
まだ間に合うかな
Can I still make it in time?
きっとここなんだろうな
This must be the place.
勝ち負けを超えてても今立ち上がれ
Rising up now, even beyond winning or losing!
不穏に揺らぐ正義
Justice trembles uneasily,
空虚に喘ぎながら
gasping in the emptiness,
それでも希望を狂い求める
yet still madly seeking hope.
守るべきものがあるはず
There must be something worth protecting,
守るべき人がいるはず
there must be someone worth protecting.
覚悟はいいか
Are you prepared?
脆弱な心を叩け
Strike down your fragile heart!
君は君をかけてでも立ち上がるんだ
You will stand up even if you put everything on the line!
不穏に揺らぐ正義
Justice trembles uneasily,
空虚に喘ぎながら
gasping in the emptiness,
それでも希望を狂い求める
yet still madly seeking hope.
守るべきものがあるはず
There must be something worth protecting,
守るべき君がいるはず
there must be you, whom I must protect.
歌ってばかりじゃだめだこりゃ！
Just singing all the time won't cut it!
絶唱！！！
Zesshou!!!
Listen to my song...
僕の声は聞こえていますか
Can you hear my voice?
please tell me...
答えのない虚構の空目指し fly far away
Aiming for the hollow sky without answers, fly far away.
言葉じゃ足りないから 僕のすべて受け止めて
Because words aren't enough, accept my everything.
営業できない したくないよ 初めて知るたか〜く
I can't do business, I don't want to, learning for the first time... high!
君に歌うよ 永遠の始まりを
I'll sing to you of the beginning of eternity.
だから笑って誰よりも熱く 誰よりも強く抱き締めるよ
So smile, warmer than anyone, holding you tighter than anyone.
震える心 揺さぶればいい
Just shake your trembling heart.
何かが動き出す 僕等
Something begins to move, we...
きっと生まれた日から 出会える日をずっと探してたんだ
Surely, ever since the day we were born, we've been searching for the day we'd meet.
風の鳴く夜は 思い出して 共に奏でた
On nights when the wind howls, remember the melody we played together.
奇跡 天に舞うよ
Miracles dance up to the heavens.
僕の想いは届いていますか？チュワーンマイ！
Has my feeling reached you? Chuwan my!
触れ合う度もどかしさが募る プライムはプライ！
Every time we touch, frustration grows, prime is pry!
いつも避けてばかりだ
I've always been avoiding you.
明日を見失いそうで 傷付けないように
As if losing sight of tomorrow, trying not to hurt you,
傷付かないように 嘘だけが増えていく
trying not to get hurt, only lies keep increasing.
だから笑って痛いくらいに苦しい程にそう愛しいから
So smile, so painfully, so agonizingly, because you are so dear to me.
求める気持ち抑えきれない自分が怖かった
I was scared of myself for not being able to hold back my desire.
やっと…体中巡る本能のリズムに
Finally... to the rhythm of instinct coursing through my body,
気付いたんだ
I realized it.
もう二度と君を離さないよ
I will never let you go again.
幾つもの昨日がね 未来を照らす
Numerous yesterdays illuminate the future.
この身朽ち果てても 伝えたいものがある 響け命の歌
Even if this body decays, there is something I want to convey. Resound, song of life!
彼方へ羽ばたいて
Fluttering away to the distance...
だから笑って誰よりも熱く誰よりも強く抱き締めたい！
So smile, warmer than anyone, holding you tighter than anyone!
震える心揺さぶればいい
Just shake your trembling heart.
何かが動き出す僕等
Something begins to move, we...
きっと生まれた日から出会える日をずっと探してたんだ
Surely, ever since the day we were born, we've been searching for the day we'd meet.
風の鳴く夜は思い出して共に紡いだ
On nights when the wind howls, remember what we wove together.
奇跡 天を描くよ
Miracles draw across the heavens.
そーれ それ それ それ そーれ
Sore sore sore sore sore!
そーれ それ それ それ そーれ [斬！]
Sore sore sore sore sore! [Slash!]
そーれ それ それ それ そーれ
Sore sore sore sore sore!
おりゃおりゃおりゃおりゃ よっしゃあーーーッ！
Orya orya orya orya Yossyaaahh!
よっしゃあ漢唄
Yossyaa Otokouta
男か 男か
Man or man,
男が燃える
a man burns bright!
それが定めよ
That is his destiny,
男！
a man!
やりもてえ 弓もてえ ほらおふけえ
Take up spears, take up bows, behold!
行くぞわ 男の花舞台
Here we go, a man's grand stage!
肉断たせ 胸断たせ さいごませ
Flesh torn, chest torn, push forward!
弓手兜 束ね
Helmets aligned,
尻尾を 引っ掛け
tails hooked!
幾千万の
Across tens of millions of—
敵陣冥加がけ切り込め！
Charge headlong into enemy ranks!
砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！ 砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！
Smash! Cry out! Shake the earth!
地獄の馬首元駆ける魔物に泥を
Mud on the demons galloping by the demon horses' necks!
砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！ ゆけ！ 砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！
Smash! Cry out! Shake! Go! Smash! Cry out! Shake!
舞って見せようぞ 兜木もいい
Let us dance it out, even with broken helmets!
それそれそれそれ それそれそれそれ
Sore, sore, sore, sore!
よっしゃあ！
Let's go!
男 男 男が燃える
Man, man, a man burns bright!
男が惚れる
A man falls in love!
命短し恋せよ男
Life is short, fall in love, men!
男 男 男が燃える それが定めよ 男
Man, man, a man burns, that is his destiny, man!
この影灯すは 茨がくれの鉄甲と
Lighting this shadow with thorny gauntlets
前だけ違う馬にてそろ
and horses heading straight ahead!
はあっ！
Haah!
吠えろや 吠えや かちどきを
Howl, let out the cries of victory!
目でてみれば ちやりの男だぜ
When you look closely, you're a true man!
桜の孤独 散りて夢
The loneliness of cherry blossoms, scattering into a dream,
死ぬわ定めか 命はなと切れ
is death our destiny? Sever life and let it go!
独り笑う
Laughing alone,
戦場がけきりこめ
charge headlong into the battlefield!
砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！ 砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！
Smash! Cry out! Shake! Smash! Cry out! Shake!
唸り上げろ われがよりよだちの血がしぶく
Roar aloud as our blood splashes forth!
砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！ 砕け 叫べ 揺らせ！
Smash! Cry out! Shake! Smash! Cry out! Shake!
花の契り いざかぶき舞う
A floral pact, now let us dance boldly!
それそれそれそれ それそれそれそれ
Sore, sore, sore, sore!
よっしゃあ！
Let's go!
男 男 男が燃える
Man, man, a man burns bright!
色は匂へと 散りぬる男
Though flowers bloom and scatter, a man remains!
男 男 男が燃える
Man, man, a man burns bright!
散って花咲け 男
Scatter and bloom, man!
男 男 男が惚れる
Man, man, a man falls in love!
命短し恋せよ男
Life is short, fall in love, men!
男 男 男が燃える
Man, man, a man burns bright!
それが定めよ 男
That is his destiny, man!
笑って散りゆけ 男
Scatter with a smile, man!
それが定めよ 男
That is his destiny, man!
それそれそれそれ それそれそれそれ
Sore, sore, sore, sore!
おらおらおらおら よっしゃあ！
Ora, ora, ora, ora! Let's go!
下弦の月が 朧に揺れる夜を
The waning moon shines dimly in the night,
包む闇も
wrapped in gathering clouds,
張り付けられた 巣食う雛からめる
trapped chicks entangled in a cruel trap,
非情の罠
a ruthless fate.
嗟嘆 今も燻る
Alas, still smoldering,
想い胸に刃と宿ば
feelings dwelling in the heart as a blade—
水の様に優しく 花の様に激しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
宿命られた涙を 瞳の奥 閉じても
Even if you close the fated tears deep in your eyes,
あなたを 瞼が覚えているの
your eyelids still remember you.
無明のフチで 終局を待つ私
Waiting for the end on the edge of the abyss,
踏みにじられた 恋を
I hold my trampled love
両手に包んだまま もう償えない
in both hands, unable to make amends anymore.
共に辿る黄泉路を
Let's walk the path to Hades together.
水の様に優しく 花の様に激しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
宿命られた涙を 瞳の奥 閉じても
Even if you close the fated tears deep in your eyes,
あなたを 瞼が覚えているの
your eyelids still remember you.
水の様に優しく 花の様に激しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
宿命られた涙を 瞳の奥 閉じても
Even if you close the fated tears deep in your eyes,
流れる血潮 止められない
the flowing blood cannot be stopped.
蜜の様に零れて 徒の様に散りゆく
Spilling like honey, scattering fruitlessly like dust,
儚い祈りを掻き消して
wiping out our faint prayers.
宿命られた二人を 青い闇が裂いても
Even if blue darkness tears apart our fated two,
あなたと辿る隠り世まで
I will follow you to the hidden world.
水の様に優しく 花の様に激しく
Gentle as water, fierce as a flower,
震える刃で貫いて
pierce through with a trembling blade!
You're already dead 'cause I
will never love you now
and maybe when you're going back to home
I'm already gone
You're already dead
Sometimes I think about
when you always stay in my arms
Please tell me why I can't love you when I see your face now
何度 「愛」 が 失くな って
「嘘」に変わ り 果て て も
新しい 感情 に は なり果て ず
I'm sorry for you...
You're already dead 'cause I
will never love you now
and maybe when you're going back to home
I'm already gone
今だけじゃなく 僕だけじゃない
この世界中の 何処にも
君を愛する者はいない
何時か僕と君がした約束は果たされず
僕らはバラバラに砕け散った
あの日の2人のように同じ気持ちじゃないと知らずに居なくなってしまうのなら...
You're already dead 'cause I
will never love you now
and maybe when you're going back to home
I'm already gone
何度目の愛? 何度目の嘘?
この世界中の 誰でも 僕を
愛するべきじゃない
You're already dead, and you?
You're already dead and you're already dead!
You're already dead 'cause I
will never love you now
and maybe when you're going back to home
I'm already gone
今だけじゃなく 僕だけじゃない
この世界中の 何処にも
君を愛する者はいない
人参DUEL
人参のDUEL
抜け!!
Catch the Moment
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
後悔は 苦い味残して
いつも 何で? 肝心なこと言えないまま
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
Quietly, I inhaled the sigh I breathed out,
後悔は苦い味残して
Regrets only left a bitter taste.
いつも なんで? 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it always like this? Unable to say what matters most,
次の 朝日が顔を出してる
The next morning sun is showing its face.
嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
Slicing up the hateful fate with a knife,
もう一度やり直したら キミに出会えないかも
If I started over, maybe I couldn't meet you.
やり直したなら
If I could start over,
キミに出会えないかも
maybe I couldn't have met you.
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
The moment my voice echoed, it all begins.
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if my wishes come true,
終わらない願い
this hope has no end.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
Sweating and running, the second hand of the world
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
will leave behind me, who stopped at some point.
あと何回キミと笑えるの?
How many more times can I smile with you?
試してるんだ僕を
It's testing me.
Catch the Moment
一個 幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count a piece of happiness,
変わっていく 未来に怯えてしまうけど
I get scared of the ever-changing future,
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
but let's nurture the seeds of love with care.
大切に育てよう
Nurturing them preciously,
分厚い雲も やがて突き破るかな
will we eventually break through the thick clouds?
キミの声が響いた 全身を通って
Your voice echoed through my entire body,
心臓のドアをノックしている
knocking on the door of my heart.
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ 信じたいから
Even with 'cowardice', I'll open it because I want to believe.
何もないと思ったはずの足元に いつか深く確かな根を生やす
At my feet where I thought was nothing, deep and certain roots will eventually grow.
嵐の夜が来たとしても 揺らいだりはしない
Even if a stormy night comes, I will never waver.
追い付いたり 追い越したり
Catching up, overtaking one another,
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
and suddenly when you become hard to understand,
息をしたタイミングが合うだけで
just the timing of our breathing matching up
嬉しくなったりして
makes me so happy.
集めた一秒を永遠にして行けるかな
Can we make every gathered second last for eternity?
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
The moment my voice echoed, it all begins.
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if my wishes come true, over and over,
終わらない願い
this hope has no end.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
Sweating and running, the second hand of the world
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
will leave behind me, who stopped at some point.
あと何回キミと笑えるの?
How many more times can I smile with you?
試してるんだ僕を
It's testing me.
Catch the Moment
逃さないよ僕は
I won't let it slip away,
この瞬間を掴め
grasp this moment!
Catch the Moment
次回 集結の園へ 楽しみだな
[Next: To the Garden of Convergence! I'm so excited...]
スーパーペチBONUS
[SUPER PECHI BONUS]
花なら 散りゆく
If it's a flower, it scatters
夢なら 果てなく
If it's a dream, endlessly
それなら 涙は何処へと 還らん
Then where do the tears return to?
仕組まれている 終結さえも 求め過ぎてた 答えなら
Even the devised conclusion, if it's an answer I sought too much
記号の中で 泳ぎ疲れて 行き着く先は ただの「カリソメ」
Tired of swimming within symbols, the destination reached is merely transient
仕組まれている 終結さえも
Devising a plan, even the conclusion
求め過ぎてた 答えなら
what you sought was far too much, if I were to answer
記号の中で
Inside the symbols
泳ぎ疲れて 行き着く先は ただのカリソメ
tired from swimming, the destination is merely transient
長い 時 はなれても 知っている
A long time although we are separated, I know
必ず 呼び合う
we will certainly call out to each other
絆を 運命と呼ぶ事
to these bonds, calling it fate
運命と呼ぶ事
calling it fate
抱いて 抱きしめても 抜け出せない
Embrace it, embrace it tightly, so tightly till you cannot slip away
定められた 境から
from an established boundary
溶けて なくなる ほどの進化へと
go ahead and melt, an evolution towards the point of nothing
おかえりなさい
Welcome back
白い 結晶が ふりそぐ都市 全ては 包まれるだけ
The white gentleness graces the city, wrapping everything
誰が 決めた訳でもない 夢を
A dream nobody decided
おかえりなさい
Welcome back
心のままに
As your heart desires
君の瞳に
In your eyes
映るその自分 何を想って 何を見ている
The shadow reflected in your eyes, what are you thinking, what are you seeing?
感じることに 信じることに 揺だねることに 怯えるようになる
To your feelings, to your beliefs, to what you've devoted yourself to, you've become a coward
長い 時
A long time
待っていた 微笑んで 支えになりましょう
I've been waiting, smiling, let's become your support
孤独で 天に願うのなら
If you are wishing to the heavens alone
いつか 繰り返す 輪廻の出口
Someday the exit of the cycle of life
さらにその先の みちも
Furthermore, the path beyond it also
きっと 出会えると 信じて泣こう
Surely we will meet each other, so let's believe and cry
おやすみなさい
Good night
赤い 血潮が 渦巻く 波間 寄せては返す いとなみ
The red sadness whirling between the waves, the tide comes and goes
愛し 愛され 一つになるまで
Love until we become one
おやすみなさい
Good night
時は 満ちるから
Because the time is ripe
長い 時
A long time
はなれても 知っている
although we are separated, I know
必ず 呼び合う
we will certainly call out to each other
絆を 運命と呼ぶ事
to these bonds, calling it fate
抱いて 抱きしめても 抜け出せない
Embrace it, embrace it tightly, so tightly till you cannot slip away
定められた 境から
from an established boundary
溶けて なくなる ほどの進化へと
go ahead and melt, an evolution towards the point of nothing
おかえりなさい 白い 結晶が ふりそぐ都市 全ては 包まれるだけ
Welcome back, the white gentleness graces the city, wrapping everything
誰が 決めた訳でもない 夢を
A dream nobody decided
おかえりなさい
Welcome back
心のままに
As your heart desires
おやすみなさい
Good night
いや、これまで当たりがずっと続いてるペコな！
Hey, I've been on a winning streak this whole time, Peko!
ということで、そんな皆さんどうも、ペコです！
So with that said, hello everyone, it's Peko!
今年もあります、うさだペコら誕生日記念2025グッズ発売会えい！
We've got it this year too, the Usada Pekora 2025 Birthday Commemoration Goods Release Presentation, yay!
ということで、1つ目は、こちら！
So, the first item is right here!
Tシャツ！
A T-shirt!
おなじみの憂姫はぐれ先生に描いてもらったペコなんですけども、いつもとはちょっと違ったかっこいいペコらのデザインペコ！
It was drawn by the familiar Yuki Hagure-sensei, and it's a cool Pekora design a bit different from usual, Peko!
是非ともね、これを着てたくさんお出かけしていってくれたら嬉しいペコ。
I'd be really happy if you wear this and go out lots, Peko.
2つ目は、こちら！
The second one is right here!
ランダムじゃらじゃらアクリルキーホルダー！
Random Jala-Jala Acrylic Keychains!
スロットの絵柄にちなんだペコらをまるえり先生に描いてもらったペコ、かわいくないペコか？
Pekora themed after slot symbols, drawn by Maru Eri-sensei. Aren't they cute, Peko?
是非ともね、あのスロットの絵柄ペコなので、同じ絵柄を3つそろえてジャックポット狙ってみてほしいペコ！
Since they're slot symbol designs, I hope you try to collect three of the same symbol and aim for the jackpot, Peko!
3つ目は、こちら！
The third one is right here!
ぺこ推しバッグ！
Peko-Oshi Bag!
最近ね、痛バを作ってくれてる人をよく見かけるペコなので、野うさぎのためにぺこらバージョンも作ってみたペコ！
Lately, I often see people making itabags, so I made a Pekora version for Usagi too, Peko!
たくさんね、もうじゃらじゃらじゃらじゃらつけて、もうライブだったりとかイベントとかに持ってってほしいペコです！
I want you to load it up with lots of keychains and take it to lives or events, Peko!
そして、4つ目は、こちら！
And the fourth one is right here!
どんちゃんカードホルダー！
Don-chan Card Holder!
もうさっきの鞄につけてもよし、チェキカードを入れるもよし、もうなんでもカード入れてくれ！
You can attach it to the bag from earlier, or put cheki cards in it, put any card you want in there, Peko!
ということで、こちら、フルセット購入特典で
And so, as for this full set purchase bonus,
チェキ風ブロマイドカードもさっきのカードホルダーにも入れるべき、もう入れてくださいペコ是非ともね！
the cheki-style bromide card should be put into that card holder from earlier. Please definitely put it in, Peko!
あの今回も直筆サインを頑張るペコですので、是非ともね、みんなお手に取っていただけたら嬉しいペコです！
Since I'll be working hard on handwritten autographs this time too, I'd be so happy if everyone could pick one up, Peko!
そしてそして、なんとホロライブカード特典もあるみたいペコです！
And what's more, it looks like there's also a Hololive Card bonus, Peko!
タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、去年から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてくるペコ！
As a full set bonus for the talent premium goods, you'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game released since last year, Peko!
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでご購入された方のみ対象ペコですので、ご注意ください！
Please note that the cards are only for those who purchased through the Hololive Production Official Shop, Peko!
いや、この後もね、面会があるので、それもお楽しみに！ということで
Well, I have a meet-and-greet after this too, so look forward to that! So...
あれ？グッズ紹介結構長いことやったはずペコなんだけど、
Huh? I'm sure I spent a pretty long time introducing the merch, Peko,
当たり全然、え？
but hitting nothing at all... huh?
来てなくないペコか？これ
Isn't it not coming up, Peko? This...
やばくないペコか？おわっちゃわねペコか？
Isn't that bad, Peko? Is it over, Peko?
やばいやばい！
Yabai yabai!
え？終わった？
Eh? It's over?
まだ野うさぎたちとじゃがれぶしを見ていないペコ！
I haven't seen the Jagare-bushi with the Usagi yet, Peko!
ミーモ ミー モミモ ミ モモ モー ミモ パラ ミカ タラ ミカ go! go! go!
Me-mo, me, mo-mi-mo, mi, mo-mo, mo, mi-mo, para, mi-ka, tara, mi-ka go! go! go!
早く君と踊りたいから
Because I want to dance with you soon,
今夜も楽しみワクワクベイビー
I'm excited and thrilled for tonight too, baby.
長い髪を振り乱してる
Tossing my long hair around,
負けちゃいそうだよパラパラダンシング
I feel like I'm gonna lose dancing parapara.
月がなくても変身するぜ狼男はラブリーわおわお！
Transforming even without a moon, werewolf boys are lovely, wao wao!
キュッと振って腰腰振ってハートがもうてれこにクリボンド yeah!
Swaying tight, shaking my hips, my heart is already tangled up, yeah!
ミーモ ミー モミモ ミ モモ モー ミモ パラ ミカ タラ ミカ go! go! go!
Me-mo, me, mo-mi-mo, mi, mo-mo, mo, mi-mo, para, mi-ka, tara, mi-ka go! go! go!
フライデーナイト サタデーナイト
Friday night, Saturday night,
リッチな遊びさ バブバブバブリー
Rich play, bub-bub-bubbly.
フェロモン足りなきゃ vipで特注マカマカ
If pheromones aren't enough, custom maca-maca at VIP.
あっ！マカ一気！
Ah! Down the maca all at once!
揺れるハートに飛び込んで行くトコまで行っておかえりハッピー
Dive into the swaying heart, go all the way, welcome back happy!
熱いまなざしで落として優しく口づけドキッときっ！
Drop me with a passionate gaze, a gentle kiss, doki-to-ki!
切なくなるほど可愛い
So cute it hurts,
壁紙にさせてくれたらラッキー
Lucky if you let me be your wallpaper!
オール最後は昇天
The very end of the night is ascension,
向こうの世界でパヤッパヤッ
Paya-paya in the world beyond.
Good night ベイビー sexy レディ
Good night baby, sexy lady,
今宵はノリノリ
Tonight we're in high spirits.
Moon night ベイビー cuite レディ
Moon night baby, cutie lady,
朝までバリバリ
Full blast until morning.
ミーモ ミー モミモ ミ モモ モー ミモ パラ ミカ タラ ミカ go! go! go!
Me-mo, me, mo-mi-mo, mi, mo-mo, mo, mi-mo, para, mi-ka, tara, mi-ka go! go! go!
汗が光る 色を恋う熱
Sweat gleaming, passion yearning for color,
つましたサンドで見つめるバービー
gazing as a Barbie in a stuffed sandwich—
ところせましと ステップ踏めば
if you step all over the place,
素敵なからだが揺れるよヘイヘイ
your lovely body sways, hey hey!
意味深な気に 誘ってくるね
You tempt me with meaningful vibes,
負けちゃいられない 睨めっこアップップ
I can't afford to lose this staring game, up-up!
冗談じゃんね わからせるから
Just kidding, I'll make you understand—
一緒にアゲンを観ようよベイビー
let's watch the game again together, baby!
じゃじゃじゃな やるじゃな
Aren't you bold, aren't you skilled?
気を抜けば 1まちまち おねだり放題
If you let your guard down, demands run wild!
おしおき済むなら まずは乾杯
If punishment is done, let's toast first—
付け シャンパン それ一気
order champagne and bottom's up!
眩しいくらい
Dazingly
華やいで
glamorous,
飲み込まれそうに 輝くレイディ
a lady shining as if about to be swallowed up—
ハレムナイト叶えたい
I want to make a harem night come true!
たまにはよりどりみどり飛び出い
Every now and then, let's leap out in a variety of choices!
これでもホントは 素直さ
Even so, honestly, being obedient
マジメで誠実 売り込みたいね
and sincere is what I want to sell!
マメな男は モテるはず
Attentive men should be popular,
そんな下心 見え見え
but such ulterior motives are plain to see!
Dancing ベイビー Stepping レディ
Dancing baby, stepping lady,
踊るよ響き響き
dancing to the echoing vibrations!
Tiny ベイビー Honey レディ
Tiny baby, honey lady,
脱いだらバリバリ
once you take it off, you're all fired up!
落としたつもりで
Thinking I dropped it,
すすりと腕をすり抜ける
slipping smoothly past your arm—
ふわりと漂う
floating softly on
魔法のコロンで
a magical cologne.
ずっとそばにいてほしいの
I want you to stay by my side always,
妙に慣れたセリフも ちょっと惑わされてもいいほどに
even if I get a little swayed by your oddly practiced lines—
君に夢中だよときめき
I'm crazy about you, my heart flutters!
揺れるハートに飛び込んで
Diving into a swaying heart,
行くトコまで行って おかえりハッピー
going all the way, welcome home happy!
熱い眼差しで落として
Drop me with a passionate gaze,
やさしい口づけ ときめき
a gentle kiss, fluttering heartbeat!
切なくなるほど かわいい
So cute it makes me ache,
壁ドンにさせてくれたらラッキー
I'd be lucky if you give me a kabedon!
オールの最後は 宵遁
The end of the night is an all-nighter escape—
向こうの世界でパヤパヤ
high in the world beyond, paya paya!
Good Night ベイビー Sexy レディ
Good night baby, sexy lady,
今宵はノリノリ
tonight we're in high spirits!
Moon Light ベイビー Cutie レディ
Moonlight baby, cutie lady,
朝までバリバリ
going hard until morning!